This is a question that has puzzled scientists for a long time. Why exactly do we yawn?
这是一个困扰科学家们很久的问题：我们究竟为什么会打哈欠呢？
In a recent breakthrough, scientists have discovered the part of the brain responsible for contagious yawning.
最近的一项突破中，科学家们发现了大脑中负责传染性打哈欠的部分。
It‘s called the primary motor cortex, and controls movement in the body.
它被称为初级运动皮层，控制着身体的运动。
When it triggers it makes us yawn.
当它被触发时，就会让我们打哈欠。
But we can’t choose to yawn - it‘s an involuntary imitation of other people.
但我们不能选择打哈欠——这是一种对他人的无意识的模仿。
You know how it goes: your friend yawns, you yawn.
你知道是怎么回事：你的朋友打哈欠，你也打哈欠。
Knowing which section of the brain is involved is only part of the answer.
知道大脑的哪个部分参与其中只是答案的一部分。
There is still a deeper question of ’why‘.
仍然存在一个更深层次的“为什么”的问题。
And we don’t only yawn when others do, we sometimes yawn alone.
而且我们不只是在他人的时候才打哈欠，有时我们也会独自打哈欠。
So, let‘s start with the physiological theories behind yawning.
那么，让我们从打哈欠背后的生理学理论开始说起。
As far back as 400BC, Greek physician Hippocrates speculated that yawning released harmful gases from the body, like “steam escaping from a cauldron”.
早在公元前400年，希腊医生希波克拉底就推测打哈欠会释放出身体里的有害气体，就像“从大锅里冒出来的蒸汽”。
His colourful theory is now, sadly, discounted.
遗憾的是，他那生动有趣的理论现在已经不予采信了。
A more recent idea suggests that we yawn in order to cool down the brain.
最近的一种观点认为，我们打哈欠是为了给大脑降温。
Just like a busy computer processor, our brains can overheat.
就像一个忙碌的电脑处理器一样，我们的大脑也可能会过热。
Psychologist Gordon Gallup from the University at Albany has argued that the act of yawning delivers a rush of oxygen to the brain, helping us think more clearly.
奥尔巴尼大学的心理学家戈登·盖洛普认为，打哈欠的动作会给大脑输送一股氧气，帮助我们更清晰地思考。
What about the connection between yawning and tiredness?
那么打哈欠和疲倦之间有什么联系呢？
We certainly yawn more when we‘re feeling sleepy or sluggish, but why is this?
当我们感到昏昏欲睡或懒散的时候，我们肯定会打更多哈欠，但这是为什么呢？
Theories that it helps give the body extra energy are largely discredited, as we don’t yawn when we exercise, a time when we definitely need more get-up-and-go!
认为打哈欠能给身体提供额外能量的理论在很大程度上已经不可信了，因为我们在锻炼的时候不会打哈欠，而锻炼的时候我们肯定是需要更多精力的！
Psychologist Catriona Morrison from the University of Leeds says yawning is an ancient reflex.
利兹大学的心理学家卡特里奥娜·莫里森说，打哈欠是一种古老的反射。
She told the BBC that it may have started in “the days of cavemen when someone had to be on watch all the time - yawning increases cerebral blood flow so can improve alertness.”
她告诉BBC，这可能始于“穴居人的时代，那时必须有人一直保持警惕——打哈欠会增加大脑的血流量，因此可以提高警觉性。”
What about our friends‘ contagious yawning?
那我们朋友之间的传染性打哈欠是怎么回事呢？
Some think it comes down to empathy.
一些人认为这归结于共情。
While all vertebrate mammals yawn, only humans and chimpanzees ’catch‘ yawns from others.
虽然所有有脊椎的哺乳动物都会打哈欠，但只有人类和黑猩猩会“传染”别人的哈欠。
Studies have shown we yawn more frequently when in the company of close relatives and friends.
研究表明，当我们和近亲及朋友在一起时，我们打哈欠的频率会更高。
Could yawning actually help us cement our closest relationships?
打哈欠实际上能帮助我们巩固最亲密的关系吗？
If it does, next time you yawn in company, don‘t feel too embarrassed.
如果确实如此，下次你在别人面前打哈欠的时候，别觉得太尴尬。
You‘re just showing off your people skills.
你只是在展示你的人际交往能力而已。